This was the campaign we did
to celebrate 40 years of Renoir cinema.
The briefing that came to us was something like
we want to find the answer to
what is cinema,
1 question as open as it cost
find 1 insight
and relevant to connect with the user.
We did not want
to stay in what everyone already knows about cinema.
We needed to look differently to put the viewer
at the Center and remind him that cinema is not only seen,
is lived.
Because we weren't really talking about cinema,
we were talking about who lives it,
of those who cry without expecting it,
of whom he recognizes himself in 1 story even if it is not his own,
of who leaves the room different from how he entered,
of who discovers other worlds he did not know.
And we change
the point of view of thinking about what is happening on the screen
to what happens in the armchair.
Because everything that happens to us in our armchair is also cinema.
And from this point on,
were we able to answer
what is cinema?
Cinema is you.
And that's how we build the idea,
1 spot that opens each session
in all Renoir movie theaters,
social networks that created conversation
what cinema is all about
and assets
designed to reinforce the message and at the same time
encourage subscription
to Renoir's membership club.
Sometimes we can look for 1 creative concept,
,
elegant,
complex,
when in fact
All we have to do is
walk away 1 little and change the look